howardwilson

contact

howard@watsonbox.net

github.com/watsonbox watsonbox.github.com

languages

english mother tongue fluent french

programming

♥ Ruby / Rails Ember.js, Swift, Python CSS3 & HTML5 AWS/EC2, Git, RSpec

open source

pocketsphinx-ruby ios_google_places xbmc-confreaks exportify

profile

Highly motivated I.T. professional, capable of integrating quickly into existing teams, applying relevant skills and technologies where appropriate. Experienced in achieving the highest standards of development, with careful appreciation of project timescales and resource. Good communication skills; confident and articulate.

education

2001–2004 **Computer Science** BSc Hons

The University of Warwick, England

Paris, France

First Class - 80% Average.

Freelance - Various Projects

Third Year Project - 89% awarded 'Project of the Year 2004'.

experience

2014-Now

	Ember.js, Swift/iOS, Docker/Dokku	
2012-2014	Fanzy Paris, F	rance
	Technical Team Lead / CTO Ruby on Rails 3.2, Goliath, Sinatra, AWS/EC2/RDS, Elasticsearch, Mongo Social APIs, Scrum, TDD	oDB,
2011-2012	eYeka Paris, F	rance
	Senior Developer / Technical Team Lead Ruby on Rails, Gigya Social Login/Sharing	
2010-2011	Smartdate Paris, F	rance
	Senior Developer - Contract Ruby on Rails 2.3, AWS/EC2, NoSQL stores, memcached, collaboramatching, Facebook Graph API, Scrum, TDD	ative
2009-2010	Halogen Solutions Limited Paris, F	rance
	Managing Director - Self Employed Ruby on Rails 2.2, MySQL, Linux systems administration	
2008-2009	Smart Business Communications Paris, F	rance
	EMEA e-Learning Project Manager - Contract PHP, MySQL, Ruby on Rails 2.1, Linux systems administration	
2006-2008	RM Education Plc Didcot, Oxfordshir	e, UK
	Technical Team Lead - Contract C#, ASP.NET, COM+, Transact-SQL	
2006	Sygneca Ltd Cliddesden, Hampshir	e, UK
	Web Application Developer - Contract Scala	
2004-2006	Dorset Software Services Poole, Dorse	et, UK
	.NET/C# Consultant Analyst Programmer	